<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lyon Energy Futures</title>
    <link>https://lyonef.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lyon Energy Futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 14:27:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lyonef.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>REVIEW: Triggernometry interview: ‘Climate Activism is Religion’</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/10/review-triggernometry-interview-climate-activism-is-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 14:27:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/10/review-triggernometry-interview-climate-activism-is-religion/</guid>
      <description>Triggernometry is a YouTube show and podcast run by comedians Konstantin Kisin and Francis Foster. In their most recent interview, “Climate Activism is a Religion”, editor of Human​Progress​.org Marian Tupy offers a perfect illustration of the fundamental defects that cripple conventional economic reasoning about energy. It’s well worth watching. In this extended essay, we’ll look at those defects, where they come from, and why they matters.
Marian is a well informed and engaging speaker, and there is much with which to agree in the interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Energy</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/10/net-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 12:38:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/10/net-energy/</guid>
      <description>The absurdity of ongoing attempts to replace ultra dense hydrocarbon with ultra diffuse, so-called &amp;ldquo;renewable&amp;rdquo; energy devices, is evident from the fundamental governing equation:
Net energy = (EROEI - 1) / EROEI
It establishes an unintuitive property shared by many physical systems: “Nothing happens for a long time, then everything happens all at once”.
That unintuitive behaviour has scrambled our reasoning about energy. It&amp;rsquo;s why the true energy and financial costs of attempts to replace hydrocarbon with sunbeams and summer breezes haven’t even begun to be estimated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collapsing Pension System</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/09/the-collapsing-pension-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/09/the-collapsing-pension-system/</guid>
      <description>The UK pension system is on the brink of collapse.
The Bank of England has been forced this week to buy government bonds in unlimited quantities to prevent mass defaults in UK pension funds. The solvency of many major banks is threatened. The pound is falling to historic lows.
The cause is simple. Money is produced from goods and services, which require energy. Energy expansion means more goods, services, and money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Discoveries Are Collapsing</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/07/oil-discoveries-are-collapsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:04:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/07/oil-discoveries-are-collapsing/</guid>
      <description>In my energy economics thesis 10 years ago, I plotted backdated global oil discovery annual volumes to derive an estimate of Ultimate Recoverable Reserve. I placed it at around 2 trillion barrels, some 2/3rd of the USGS estimate (see the chart below).
Discoveries are falling Fast forward to today, and Rystad Energy report 1 that the O&amp;amp;G industry discovered less than 5 billion boe in 2021 - the worst performance in 75 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Climate Science Is Not Even Wrong</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/06/why-climate-science-is-not-even-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/06/why-climate-science-is-not-even-wrong/</guid>
      <description>The persistence of “renewable” technology energy policy, pitched as a necessary solution to lurid predictions of catastrophic changes in our climate supposedly caused by our CO2 emissions, is puzzling in the face of the startling track record of the failure of those predictions.
Climate physics modellers, endlessly refitting their models to accommodate the next tranche of falsifying observational data, claim that these failures are insignificant tuning issues. Policy makers accept this excuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONS Study Shows Fewer People Dying</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/05/ons-study-shows-fewer-people-dying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/05/ons-study-shows-fewer-people-dying/</guid>
      <description>If your livelihood depends on the $500 billion-a-year climate catastrophe industry, you may want to brace yourself. This is going to hurt.
The UK’s Office for National Statistics (ONS) has issued a report1. Temperatures in the UK have risen in the last 20 years.
That’s not news, of course. Temperatures have been rising since the end of the mini-ice age in 16th Century. The increase falls well within the range of natural variation, and in the bottom 10% of the aggregate range predicted by the comically broken toy climate physics models that are the basis of alarmist claims about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Your Energy Provider Tells You to Jump</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/01/when-your-energy-provider-tells-you-to-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:15:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/01/when-your-energy-provider-tells-you-to-jump/</guid>
      <description>Scottish and Southern Energy have issued rather bracing guidance to its customers that they should eat porridge, purchase merino wool socks, cuddle pets, and do star jumps to stay warm while keeping bills down in the face of soaring energy costs.
This has the merit at least of being a more rational strategy than trying to supply the colossal power requirements of the global industrial manufacturing system with intermittent sunbeams and summer breezes, using short-lived gadgets that require for their manufacture &amp;hellip; a hydrocarbon-powered, global industrial manufacturing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transition Planning and the Oil Supply</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2019/11/energy-transition-planning-and-the-oil-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 12:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2019/11/energy-transition-planning-and-the-oil-supply/</guid>
      <description>As concern about climate change increases, so too do demands for the boycott of fossil fuel businesses, and to step up investments in renewable technology firms.
But there&amp;rsquo;s an ugly paradox at the centre of the current energy transition plan. The ultimate goal of renewable energy technology is to replace hydrocarbon as a fuel source for industrial civilisation. Yet the construction, operation, and maintenance of that technology depends on vast volumes of hydrocarbon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Surprising Benefits of Passive Houses</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2019/08/the-surprising-benefits-of-passive-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 13:26:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2019/08/the-surprising-benefits-of-passive-houses/</guid>
      <description>What it is&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s a machine for conserving space heat energy.
The building is a fairly modest two story house set into the south western slope of Edinburgh’s Corstorphine Hill in Scotland. Its precision timber frame was factory constructed offsite, and assembled on a thick aerated concrete slab. All penetrations (doors, windows, etc) are designed to eliminate thermal bridging. All joints and penetrations are taped and sealed to ensure airtightness. Ventilation is maintained by a PAUL Wärmerückgewinnung GmbH novus 300 mechanical ventilation system injecting pollen-filtered fresh air into bedrooms and public rooms, and extracting it from wet rooms for heat recovery and exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
