<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>passive housing on Lyon Energy Futures</title>
    <link>https://lyonef.com/tags/passive-housing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in passive housing on Lyon Energy Futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:15:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lyonef.com/tags/passive-housing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Your Energy Provider Tells You to Jump</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2022/01/when-your-energy-provider-tells-you-to-jump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:15:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2022/01/when-your-energy-provider-tells-you-to-jump/</guid>
      <description>Scottish and Southern Energy have issued rather bracing guidance to its customers that they should eat porridge, purchase merino wool socks, cuddle pets, and do star jumps to stay warm while keeping bills down in the face of soaring energy costs.
This has the merit at least of being a more rational strategy than trying to supply the colossal power requirements of the global industrial manufacturing system with intermittent sunbeams and summer breezes, using short-lived gadgets that require for their manufacture &amp;hellip; a hydrocarbon-powered, global industrial manufacturing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Surprising Benefits of Passive Houses</title>
      <link>https://lyonef.com/2019/08/the-surprising-benefits-of-passive-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 13:26:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lyonef.com/2019/08/the-surprising-benefits-of-passive-houses/</guid>
      <description>What it is&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s a machine for conserving space heat energy.
The building is a fairly modest two story house set into the south western slope of Edinburgh’s Corstorphine Hill in Scotland. Its precision timber frame was factory constructed offsite, and assembled on a thick aerated concrete slab. All penetrations (doors, windows, etc) are designed to eliminate thermal bridging. All joints and penetrations are taped and sealed to ensure airtightness. Ventilation is maintained by a PAUL Wärmerückgewinnung GmbH novus 300 mechanical ventilation system injecting pollen-filtered fresh air into bedrooms and public rooms, and extracting it from wet rooms for heat recovery and exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
